=== Generating PRD ===
{
  "title": "StandupSync",
  "problem_statement": "Remote engineering teams spread across multiple time zones struggle to stay aligned without disruptive synchronous daily standups that force off-hours attendance or fragment deep work time. Traditional text-based check-ins in Slack are inconsistent, easily buried, and lack structure, making it hard for engineering managers to track blockers or team progress at a glance. As remote-first engineering organizations grow, the coordination overhead compounds and existing ad-hoc solutions fail to scale. A purpose-built async standup tool integrated directly into Slack can eliminate meeting fatigue while preserving team visibility.",
  "target_users": [
    "Remote software engineers participating in daily standups across distributed time zones",
    "Engineering managers and team leads who need to track team progress and blockers without scheduling synchronous meetings",
    "DevOps and platform engineers who work on-call schedules and cannot attend fixed daily meeting times",
    "Engineering directors overseeing multiple squads who need rolled-up status visibility"
  ],
  "user_stories": [
    "As a remote software engineer, I want to receive a Slack prompt at a configurable local time each day so that I can submit my standup update without attending a live meeting",
    "As an engineering manager, I want to view a digest of all team standup responses in a single Slack thread or channel each morning so that I can identify blockers and follow up without reading scattered messages",
    "As a software engineer, I want to answer structured standup questions (yesterday, today, blockers) via a Slack modal so that my updates are consistently formatted and easy to skim",
    "As an engineering manager, I want to receive an automatic alert when a team member reports a blocker so that I can take action the same day without waiting for a sync",
    "As a remote software engineer, I want to skip a standup day with a single click and provide an optional reason so that my absence is logged without creating noise",
    "As an engineering director, I want to view weekly participation rates and blocker trends across multiple teams so that I can identify teams that are struggling or disengaged",
    "As a team lead, I want to customize the standup questions for my team so that the prompts are relevant to our current sprint and workflow",
    "As a software engineer, I want to react or comment on teammates' standup updates within Slack so that async collaboration and unblocking can happen in context"
  ],
  "acceptance_criteria": [
    "A user can install StandupSync to a Slack workspace via OAuth in fewer than 5 steps with no engineering involvement required",
    "A Slack DM prompt is delivered to each team member within 60 seconds of their individually configured standup time, verified across at least 3 different time zones in testing",
    "Standup responses submitted via a Slack modal are posted to a designated team channel as a formatted digest within 2 minutes of the submission deadline",
    "Engineering managers receive a Slack DM notification within 5 minutes whenever a team member submits a response that includes a non-empty blocker field",
    "Team members can skip a standup by clicking a single 'Skip Today' button in the Slack prompt; the skip is recorded and reflected in participation metrics",
    "Admins can create, edit, and delete standup schedules including custom questions, submission windows (15\u2013120 minutes), and participant lists through a web dashboard",
    "The web dashboard displays per-team participation rate, average response time, and open blocker count for the trailing 7 and 30 days",
    "StandupSync supports workspaces with up to 500 active users with p99 prompt delivery latency under 90 seconds",
    "Users who have not responded within 50% of the submission window receive a single automated Slack reminder; no more than one reminder is sent per standup cycle",
    "All standup response data is retained for a minimum of 90 days and exportable as CSV from the web dashboard"
  ],
  "success_metrics": [
    {
      "metric": "Weekly active teams (teams that complete at least 4 standup cycles in a 7-day period)",
      "baseline": "0 teams at launch",
      "target": "500 active teams within 6 months of GA"
    },
    {
      "metric": "Standup participation rate (percentage of prompted users who submit a response or log a skip per cycle)",
      "baseline": "Estimated 55% with unstructured Slack check-ins based on user research",
      "target": "80% participation rate averaged across all active teams within 90 days of adoption"
    },
    {
      "metric": "Time-to-install (minutes from clicking 'Add to Slack' to first standup schedule configured and saved)",
      "baseline": "No existing benchmark; target set from usability testing",
      "target": "Median time-to-install under 8 minutes for new workspace admins"
    },
    {
      "metric": "Blocker resolution time (hours between a blocker being reported in a standup and the engineer marking it resolved)",
      "baseline": "Unknown; teams currently have no structured blocker tracking",
      "target": "Median blocker resolution time under 24 hours for teams using StandupSync for 30+ days"
    },
    {
      "metric": "7-day retention rate (percentage of teams that run at least one standup in week 2 after initial setup)",
      "baseline": "0% at launch (no historical data)",
      "target": "70% 7-day team retention rate within 3 months of GA"
    }
  ],
  "risks_open_questions": [
    "Slack API rate limits may constrain prompt delivery for large workspaces; need to validate throughput capacity for workspaces with 200+ users before GA",
    "Will users experience Slack prompt fatigue if they are already members of multiple Slack bots or notification-heavy workflows? Consider an opt-out or snooze mechanism.",
    "How should StandupSync handle Slack Enterprise Grid with multiple orgs \u2014 is multi-org support required at launch or post-GA?",
    "Data privacy and compliance: standup responses may contain sensitive project information; need to confirm SOC 2 Type II scope and GDPR data residency requirements before entering European markets",
    "What is the pricing model (per seat, per team, flat rate) and how does it affect conversion from free trial \u2014 requires validation with at least 20 prospective customers before finalization",
    "Will engineering managers adopt the web dashboard, or will they prefer all visibility natively inside Slack? Need usability testing to confirm dashboard vs. Slack-native digest preference",
    "How do we handle teams that work weekends or non-standard schedules (e.g., on-call rotations) \u2014 does the scheduler support weekend prompts and irregular cadences?",
    "Risk of low adoption if Slack workspace admins are different from engineering managers who want the tool \u2014 need a clear self-serve install flow that does not require IT approval in most organizations"
  ],
  "out_of_scope": [
    "Video or voice standup recording and transcription",
    "Integration with project management tools (Jira, Linear, Asana) at launch \u2014 post-GA roadmap item",
    "Native mobile application; Slack mobile client is the mobile surface",
    "AI-generated standup summaries or natural language blocker detection at launch",
    "Support for standup workflows outside of Slack (e.g., Microsoft Teams, email) in v1",
    "Real-time synchronous meeting scheduling or calendar integrations",
    "Performance review or employee sentiment analysis based on standup content",
    "Multi-language localization beyond English at launch"
  ]
}

=== Evaluating PRD ===
{
  "scores": {
    "specificity": {
      "score": 9,
      "reason": "Requirements include precise numeric thresholds (e.g., p99 latency under 90s, delivery within 60 seconds, 15\u2013120 minute submission windows) leaving minimal ambiguity, though the blocker 'resolution' mechanism (who marks it resolved and how) is underspecified."
    },
    "measurability": {
      "score": 9,
      "reason": "All five metrics include a named metric, explicit baseline, and quantified target with timeframes, though the blocker resolution metric acknowledges an unknown baseline which slightly weakens confidence in the target."
    },
    "testability": {
      "score": 9,
      "reason": "Acceptance criteria are largely objective and verifiable with specific numeric bounds, multi-timezone test requirements, and defined UI interactions, with only minor ambiguity around 'non-empty blocker field' edge cases and formatting standards for the digest."
    },
    "user_centricity": {
      "score": 9,
      "reason": "Four distinct, well-differentiated personas are defined and each user story follows a consistent role/want/outcome format that maps directly to real pain points observed in distributed engineering workflows."
    },
    "completeness": {
      "score": 8,
      "reason": "All core PRD sections are present and detailed, including risks and out-of-scope items, but the document omits a competitive landscape analysis, monetization/pricing detail, and a phased release or milestone timeline."
    }
  },
  "overall_score": 9.0,
  "top_3_improvements": [
    "Add a competitive and alternative landscape section (e.g., Geekbot, Range, Loom standups) to contextualize differentiation and inform prioritization decisions.",
    "Specify the blocker resolution workflow end-to-end \u2014 including who can mark a blocker resolved, via which surface (Slack vs. dashboard), and how resolution state is persisted \u2014 to close the most underspecified functional gap.",
    "Include a phased rollout or milestone plan (alpha, beta, GA criteria) with dependency callouts such as SOC 2 completion and Slack API throughput validation, so engineering and go-to-market teams have a shared delivery timeline."
  ]
}
